Mashuk Sadman

mashuksadman@gmail.com +88 01726 634 711 Flat-b5, 85B/12A, Dhanmondi, Dhaka, BANGLADESH

Personal Statement

I have been working with React and native android app development for last 6-7 years and have a good experience on React JS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Reflux, JavaScript [ES7], databases, different libraries etc. as well as I have solved over 650 uva problems which are mainly related to math, algorithm, graph, dynamic programming, problem solving paradigms and data structure.

Objectives

Seeking a position in a company where I could apply my software engineering experience specially on React JS and logic related problems and contribute to the development process both as an individual and a good team player.

Skills

Technology: React Js, Redux, Redux-Saga, Reflux, JavaScript [ES7]

API: FabricJs, Google, Algolia, Facebook, Twitter, Github, Firebase, Auth0, etc.

Ides: Android Studio

DBMS: MySQL, Sqlite, Firebase, Firestore

Automation Tools: Webpack

Versioning: Git

Project Management: Scrum

Portfolio

Isomorphic - React Redux Admin Dashboard (Redq Inc.): A react-redux powered single page admin dashboard. Used progressive web application pattern, highly optimized for react application.

Reactive Pro - Redq Inc (Redq Inc.): Make searching easy for your customers. Advanced search, filter & grid plugin, powered by react-redux. It can search through post, product, custom post types, taxonomies, metadata and term metas. It has built in with geo box and location searching facility.

Mate - React Redux Material Admin Dashboard (Redq Inc.): A react-redux powered single page material admin dashboard. Used progressive web application pattern, highly optimized for react application.

Prohoree (TechCareBD): Current condition & information of Vehicles instantly featuring Real time tracking, Pin point location, Latitude & Longitude, Start Stop Report, Travel History, Speed Report etc.

Pathashala (TechCareBD): A video tube for students where everyone can watch video tutorials. OnnoRokom Pathshala offers you a different approach of learning.

Maa o shishu (10th at EATL Prothom-Alo app contest 2013): Maa o shishu has the moto to help pregnant mother & their new born child. It keeps almost all the technological help that a smart phone can provide.

4K Wallpaper (Zert Interactive): Wallpaper collection installed over 100k. This app is packed with some awesome backgrounds. It has been installed over 100,000.

CricScore (Zert Interactive): Cricket score related live wallpaper. You can set the match score as live wallpaper on your home screen.

Hepatitis (Zert Interactive): Hepatitis consciousness app in BANGLA. Its Awareness app.

Mustache Booth (Zert Interactive): This app is a simple entertainment app that allows to put a mustache, beard and funny comments on anyone or anything.

UVA Solution: Over 650 problems solved in different categories mostly related to math and algorithm.

Work Experience

Software Engineer | RedQ Inc.

July, 2016 - Present

I mainly develop react based apps here. I worked with various modules, restful apis, dashboard and wordpress plugins. I have to taste and correct bugs in their functioning. I collaborated with designers to meet customers' expectations and optimized website usability. We have to maintain the team workflow to complete programming and development tasks of different difficulty levels.

Senior Android developer | Zert Interactive

January, 2016 - June, 2016

Zert Interactive mainly deals with android and IOS apps. Among android apps I have worked over 80 projects including live wallpapers, live score streaming, custom ui generator and so on.

Assistant Software Engineer | System Resources Ltd.

March, 2015 - December, 2015

System Resources Limited (SRL) offer services for developing business application software & app, database management, IT audit and project management software & app etc. I developed android apps here.

Android developer | TechCare Ltd.

2012 - 2014

A start up for ui/ux design, mobile app development and web app development. I worked as ux developer and android apps development.

Education

	Institutions	Seassion	Result
B.Sc. in Computer	Rajshahi University of	2010-2014	3.28 out of 4.00
Science & Engineering	Engineering & Technology		
HSC	Cantonment public School	2009	5.00 out of 5.00
	& College, Rangpur		
SSC	Cantonment public School	2007	5.00 out of 5.00
	& College, Rangpur		

Awards

6th position in Code Warriors challenge 2014
Excellence Performance Award 2014, RUET
2nd position in CSE Inter Programming Contest 2014, RUET
10th position in EATL Prothom-Alo app contest 2013
1st position in CSE Fest Inter University Programming Contest 2012, RUET
Participating in ACM ICPC 3 times, 2010-12
UVA online-judge problems solved 650, ranked 514

External Links

Online CV: https://halumz.github.io **Github**: https://github.com/halumz

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mashuk-sadman-740a3b107/

UVA: http://uhunt.onlinejudge.org/id/71527

HackerRank: https://www.hackerrank.com/mashuksadman